

DEBOLINA KONAR

₱ BENGALURU, INDIA
♣ 9632624258

• DETAILS •

Bengaluru, India 9632624258 debolinatester@gmail.com

o SKILLS o

Project Management People Management Manual Testing **Automation Testing Regression Testing** API Testing(Rest Services) Postman Java Maven Mix Panel Analytics Jenkins Jira Git Cucumber Team Management Framework Design Release Management

AWS

GCP

• LANGUAGES •

English

Hindi

PROFILE

Software Engineering Lead having 12+ years of expertise across diverse projects with strong technical background. Actively involved in framework development for web and API(Rest) services. Managed/Lead multiple software quality assurance processes, ensuring high standards and helped in recruitment.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Technical Lead / Manager at Zee Limited, Bengaluru

May 2022 - March 2024

Key Responsibilities

- Lead a team of QA engineers to always deliver complete project on time and with efficiency and team collaboration along with vendor teams.
- Actively involved in API and Web functional as well as automation testing.
- Hands on with coding and development of utilities for the team.
- Developed a risk-based testing approach that prioritized bug fixes and ensured software releases are met with customer expectations.
- Managed the entire Web section of the ZEE5 OTT platform in respect to contents playability and Subscription Management.
- Helped to promote and drive a culture of continuous improvement along with new hire recruitment, ensuring a thorough onboarding process.

Sr Software Engineer at Visa, Bengaluru

February 2021 — May 2022

Worked as a key functional and automation test engineer for VDCS application.

Actively involved in Test case design, functional and automation test execution along with Test Automation framework development for Web and API testing.

Associate at J P Morgan, Bengaluru

November 2017 — January 2021

Lead a team of 6 test engineers to deliver quality assurance for consumer Banking applications like credit cards, debit cards, Mortgage, Home Loans with both front end and back-end applications for web and API automation. Debugged via Splunk to reach the RCA for the same.

Senior QA Engineer at Ness Technologies, Bengaluru

April 2016 — November 2017

Delivered Quality Assurance for Payback Client as a Test and Automation Engineer. Primarily worked for API testing via postman and automation in Java technologies.

Associate at Cognizant Technology Solutions, Bengaluru

March 2012 — March 2016

Worked in functional Testing, User Acceptance Testing, Regression Testing for GSSC (cognizant Internal Tool) and COMCAST.

EDUCATION

BTech, West Bengal University Of Technology, Kolkata

August 2007 — June 2011